it is episode
44 and everyone knows what that means
we're doing some hermit challenges I
don't know why everyone's looking
forward to this episode so much but I've
seen a lot of can't wait for episode 44
I don't know why everyone's so excited
they're almost expecting something very
odd to happen which is weird however it
is the episode that I'm going to rid
myself of all of these hermit challenge
chickens there's so so many and I think
if we do them in a montage we can get
more done at once and that montage is
this chicken do a one minute dance
Montage come on little chicken you're
going to be the first one to be
completed bye-bye now one minute hybrid
Dance Challenge Montage let's
[Music]
go say a sentence backwards I'm going to
try and say this backwards but I don't
know what it's going to look sound like
if you actually put it
Forward
ahas where a blue jumper sacrilege I
don't mind doing any of these these
other hermit challenges but this one
this one hurts spr's my
color two in
one bye
I I have something special and it only
costs whatever you want it to cost want
to buy pay up front this man knows how
to do
business what the heck what um
oh no no corales no stop stop that was
it that was
it no what do I do he's given me two
stacks of Diamonds oh goodness I've just
convinced
some hermit challenges you can get away
with anything if you say hermit
challenges in the chat randomly start
complaining in chat
[Music]
the tickets are everywhere there's a few
people online no one's saying
anything invent nicknames for all the
Hermits Rumbo G Iceman cow Ren SOG I'm
going to borrow that one from Mumbo Cub
man docky b double
[Applause]
[Music]
[Laughter]
poo oh this is looking good this is
looking really good I don't think anyone
appreciates quite how nice polished
andesite can be as a pure building block
just everything out of andesite and
you've got yourself a perfect looking
build it doesn't even need a door all it
needs is more andesite if you ask me
this oh I mean I should submit this and
get a Guinness World Record for the
nicest looking house you know what
actually it doesn't look that bad does
it and end of dance
Montage okay I have done all of the
chickens that I feel like I could have
done in that Montage not all of them
were completely doable because there are
some ones that I didn't expect to find
today and there was this one take credit
for someone else's base which is
hilarious and deserves its own couple of
minutes dedicated to it and this one do
a ptry man cameo in next episode it may
not be next episode okay it may have to
be one or two poultry man I I don't know
who he is I it takes a while to contact
him I've not seen him in quite a while
um so this one will maybe take a bit of
doing but at some point we'll do it
we'll get we'll we'll contact him feel
like Peter Parker oh yeah I know
Spider-Man and call a Hermit and just
hum I haven't hat there's no one I could
call it just hum so maybe the the
opportunity will present itself very
very soon and can we just talk talk
about the fact that I went up to corales
in his office completely unplanned he
didn't know I was
coming and I just said I've got an item
pay up front and the dude the dude is so
rich that he gives me two stacks of
diamonds he looked like he was going to
give me more but I was I was freaking
out I was expecting him to pay me in
bamboo so I don't I I messaged him he
said keep it that was the best challenge
ever that worked out and also I really
don't like this blue jumper but we're
going to wear it we're going to wear it
for this episode so now that our dancing
Montage of all the different things are
done we are going to put most of these
hermit challenges to rest they are here
in the completed challenges section and
boy that has been a bit of a weight on
my
mind these were just off the top of my
head I think my uh my favorite I think
my favorite is got to be smells KN so
you might have noticed that there is a
serious serious pile of shulker boxes
going on here this is me off camera
preparing stuff this is the next round
of barge boxes and you'll even notice
another fresh block of netherite ready
for the taking now this round of barge
boxes are going to be very different you
may remember a couple of episodes ago
there was a box in here that ended up
having a load of question marks in it
and what it did I don't know if you saw
Ren's video Ren bought it and it
basically sent him on a bit of a
treasure hunt it gave him a riddle that
led him to the mouth of this mysterious
plant and inside here there was a book
that led him somewhere else eventually
he found the prize which was a full NE
the right block and it was so successful
that particular one that I'm now going
to change the way I do Mystery barge
boxes or at least the next round of them
so this time it's going to be all
question marks and they're all going to
be treasure hunts which is really really
exciting because I think it's going to
be much more fun to play and watch and
see what you get so I've been preparing
the rewards for that but they're not
quite done yet what we do need to work
on is the mycelium resistance base now
we have actually chosen somewhere for
this base and it would be really foolish
of me to for sale there's a shop for
sale Ultra efficient concrete shop for
sale contact BDubs and scarf for a
showing this looks amazing I don't
really need a concrete shop but I might
be interested anyway we got distracted
so what we need to do is get ourselves
into the my iium resistance base we
found a location and I have been
Excavating as you can see right there
look look at me go whoa look at him go
he's he's he's oh he's Excavating and
everything okay but there's only one way
to get in and it would be foolish of me
to show on camera where the entrance is
because I can't trust any of you someone
one of you out there would go and tell
the mayor where the base entrance is so
to keep it tip toop secret we're
entering it in a much more secretive way
so the only way to get in at the moment
is with a chorus fruit let's go there we
go Zip Zip and we are in so it is a
pretty hidden location and we also found
a spawner well I found a spawner right
there which will come in handy if we
ever need to defend the place I've told
everyone where the base is and how to
get in so all there is to do is to
communicate at what the plan is build
the base
Farm my celium bread the spores and
remember it's a matter of principle so
for this room i' I've been thinking
about the design and I'm thinking a lot
of quartz is necessary and also I was
thinking for this
design the that was quite the
entrance I see found it hey man oh this
is the opportunity I call another hermit
I've got to do this entire thing by
humming this is I hate hermit challenges
so much okay I'm going to call
impulse how you doing buddy I you you're
up to a lot you've been digging MH very
nice man although the way ends a little
[Music]
weird um did you bite your tongue or
something
something no you
[Music]
good
um I think I feel like you're trying to
tell me something okay oh this this you
what words are okay the plan build the
base Farm my celium spread the
spores remember it's a matter of
principle
right why can't why can't you
talk no he's lost his
mind Brian's completely lost his mind oh
oh okay okay you don't need to talk
don't hurt yourself but here I got an
idea far my ceing he keeps hitting far
okay okay it's kind of like sign
language but not I got this he needs me
to farm my celium you're in luck I can
do that look I have shovels
I someday I'll teach you how to do the
shovel Shuffle it's
fun okay well this is very awkward
considering you're not using words but I
I'm on top of it boss we're going to
farm some melium and help spread the
spores I'm off I got work to
do it it's just too awkward to talk to
you right
now so for this design I almost want it
to be like a laboratory in here and for
that I'm going to want some smooth
smooth quartz block because it doesn't
have that pattern as a bit of a
centerpiece we have one large 5x5 block
of mycelium and like a big block of
mycelium so this is the
melium source block this is the source
of all of our power it looks a little
bit strange cuz there's not enough
mycelium at the top but you get the idea
this is the melium sword
block and I was thinking we could like
have some almost like vents coming off
of it leading dirt or mycelium out of
here so like this and then we surround
it with some Crimson trap doors and it
looks like we've got like tubes coming
out of the source block which I think
looks really cool so what I think we
need to do is actually decorate around
the source block and get it looking I
don't know know it just looks a bit
cramped in there at the moment so I
think we need to open it up a little bit
more oh diamonds more diamonds while
digging out this whole thing I managed
to get 26 diamond ores so this day with
a mixture of corales just handing me
diamonds and digging out this place I've
ended up with a lot of diamonds let's
see how many we get from this 59
diamonds not bad at all I guess we'll
add it to our increasing Diamond
stockpile I actually think that this
Source block may look more sensible as a
3X3 let's shave it down and see what it
looks like I think that looks much more
sensible actually it's just because of
this texture at the top it's a little
bit small so if we had mycelium coming
off both these sides this could be a
really cool decoration for the base also
there's this block which I've not really
used before the quartz brick and I'm
hoping to integrate this into the design
of the melium base I'm kind of just
experimenting with the quartz at the
moment what I really need to find is an
additional color I quite like the
Crimson but I'm not sure how to
integrate it yet this project is going
to be a big build because we don't just
need our source block we need a meeting
room we need a laboratory we need a
whole bunch of things and I don't want
to just go and do it all by myself I
kind of want to get everyone involved
and sort of Smash out a design that
everyone can get on board with and is
happy to build so I'm just going to
experiment with this little section for
now and see where we get there we go
that is our source block I still think
there's more to be added here but I want
to get a bit more input from the other
resistance members because I'm not
particularly happy with it I think it
looks okay don't get me wrong but it's
missing a little something something and
I'm not quite sure what it is but the
lab and the base
has been officially started and I also
noticed there's a whole lot of fish
there so I think we ought to add another
quick list of things to do in the base
so we need to think about certain things
a source block room which I've kind of
taken care of a meeting room where we
can all sit down and talk about our
plans to take over the shopping district
I mean resist Scar and a lab testing
facility and of course an exit there's
actually at the moment no way out of
here there's a way in but there's no way
out and of course ethos bedroom so I
think that's a pretty decent start and
I'll leave it kind of up to the meeting
we have with the other resistance
members that actually looks pretty cool
framed in there look at that the melium
source Block it's pretty it's lit pretty
nicely actually I just need to figure
out what else to do with this particular
room now I want to head back to the base
as it is episode 44 and for some reason
you guys are expec expecting something I
think I know what it is you want me to
work on the back of the
mansion that's what you want so that's
what we're going to do we're going to
travel to the back of the hermitcraft
mansion and we're going to do some
building man it's a pretty Mammoth task
to do all of this building all this
terrain by
myself you know the back doesn't really
look very good you know none of this
looks good the whole mansion was a
mistake there's no point in this whole
thing I'm never going to do the back I
don't want to do the back and it'll the
the thing will never be complete I will
never ever finish this Mansion properly
so I don't know what the point is I
don't know what the point of this whole
thing is it's it's ugly I'm ugly I I
can't make anything good you know what
we should just we should just get rid of
this whole thing that's right I don't
want any of this anymore none of it none
of it none of it all of this hard work
is going to go to waste because everyone
is pressuring me to finish the back of
the mansion and guess what I don't want
to finish the back of the Mansion you
think this is a joke don't you you think
I'm not going to do it I'm going to do
it this Mansion sucks no one likes it I
don't know why I bother this should be
enough to say goodbye to this awful
awful build I never want to see it again
that's right no it's real it's happening
it's going up oh my
goodness goodbye Manion oh
[Music]
no goodbye man oh my goodness what a
mess oh oh no it didn't even want to
load my Mansion my beautiful mansion
it's all God pesky bird what have you
done really is a pesky bird at least you
got out of there somehow oh no oh no not
even the Chariot survived this is what
you get for pressuring me to do the back
of the Mansion well now there's no front
of the Mansion
either so I think that's what it would
look like if I did have a breakdown in
episode 44 you know I'm not a therapist
right
I think that definitely counts as having
a breakdown in episode
44 so I think we can take down finally
these fences that were blocking in the
chickens and we can submit not the final
chicken unfortunately this wasn't
actually the last challenge that I had
to do but I had to go big because I just
saw so many comments that were saying I
can't wait to see him have a breakdown
in you go this episode I feel has been
one of the best that I've ever made and
if you are enjoying it this is going to
be one of those rare times that I ask
you to subscribe if you genuinely like
watching my videos I don't normally ask
it but on episodes like this where I've
put in the extra mile and don't worry
the Mansion is completely safe I rebuilt
it in like 5 Seconds it was super
[Laughter]
easy oh hermit challenges we've done an
awful lot today but yet got an awful not
done you know what I mean we we did a
lot but also achieved nothing I think
that's what hermitcraft is all about
doing Lots achieving nothing but I have
got myself a fresh Decked Out dungeon
key that I would love to go and use in
the Decked Out mini game things that I
need reminding to do cuz I'm now
actually fresh out of uh sugarcane I
need to finish that sugarcane farm it's
not going to take me long in fact I've
actually done quite a lot of it it under
here I've set up oh my I've been
Excavating quite a lot of it I need to
get get out of
here that's a nightmare oh ex oh there's
no one under there oh my goodness oh my
goodness whoa ah
they've I've caused more damage than I
was fixing I don't know what set off
this explosion down here oh for goodness
sake I'm going to leave before I make
this work how did they get oh there's
whacka all going
[Music]
on okay we're getting out of here cuz
I've literally come over here saying I
need to make my sugarcane farm and
finish it and all I've achieved is
breaking it so just I need reminding
that needs doing cuz if it if it doesn't
get done I'm going to run out of rockets
and agree in without oh look at that
Arrow directly in my schnos if I run out
of rockets I'm going to be a sad boy to
deck out we go
no I hope no one's in deck out I'm
hoping that there is another box
somewhere for me to find what is this is
this Cub fan he's spying on the office
of the mayor I thought you were with the
mayor the melan resistance grows there's
patches of it everywhere I can't seem to
find a box anywhere but there are lots
of things going round roads now okay
let's take our one dungeon key and go
and play decked out I have actually got
some Decked Out coins and if I can get
myself an ender pearl ah there's none
for sale challenge Compass 15 coins
let's give it a go there we go challenge
Compass let's go and do a decked out run
I'm ready I'm feeling confident let's
enter the dungeon right so we've
actually got two two compasses all the
stuff is off click the Box we've
submitted our cards we've got two
compasses and the games
begin I think the ad the admin's in
there right we're going two different
directions I reckon we go this way
first no no rager no rager no rager away
away away
oh it still go for me oh oh that was
that was a pro
skip wait okay so I need to actually
focus on which Compass I'm going to
follow this one is over this
direction I
really I really really don't oh there's
oh there's a pit of ravages for real no
no no no no no no no no I'm going to hit
get a dead end I don't know what to
do there's a ravager over here somewhere
as well oh he's still coming for me oh
I'm going to get
trapped I'm going to get so
trapped oh
no
okay oh
jeez this is the
worst oh
man I don't know what to do
I have no idea what to
do okay let's go for this one
first okay we need to head that
direction see this is what I wanted to
jump down into but I'm still too scared
to do it maybe another time when we
haven't got our challenge compass with
us
no no no no no no this has been the
worst run
ever this has been the worst run there's
literally ravages
everywhere oh and now it's the forest
which is definite
death there's nearly always a ravager
here I'm going to run out of Sprint
soon oh man
okay looks like we're getting
close no I can't quite figure out where
this
goes oh no skeletons come on get through
I can't afford to take
damage literally oh oh oh it's there
it's it's here somewhere no
I no I've had to abandon my
compass this game is this game is too
challenging okay new
plan I'm pretty sure it's there
it's on this block so it must be
under uhoh no no
no that was the that was the most
difficult
run
ever oh and I forgot my bed great let's
get our stuff back that was that was
rough that was really rough I lost my
compass I couldn't find where it was I
couldn't find anything I lost my coins
that was that was really difficult I
could not focus enough I kept getting
hit by ravages
everywhere H Beast sense
stealth stealth and we'll go for a
stealth well that was certainly scary
that was certainly a scary run and I've
run out of keys so there's not a lot
else for us to do other than say
thank you very much for watching
everyone I hope that I find another key
soon and I shall see you in the next
episode where I hope to finish my
sugarcane farm and hopefully get the
base to the mycelium resistance
complete
s up